<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2026-02-08T08:16:22-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><subtitle>Welcome! This is Sadamori Kojaku&apos;s personal webpage.
</subtitle><author><name>Sadamori Kojaku</name></author><entry><title type="html">The invisible cyborgs</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/invisible-cyborg.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The invisible cyborgs" /><published>2026-02-07T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2026-02-07T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/invisible-cyborg</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/invisible-cyborg.html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;building-my-parts&quot;&gt;Building my parts&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While reading &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dtlarson.com/feed-the-beast&quot;&gt;Darek Larson’s blog&lt;/a&gt;, I daydreamed about a scene from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imdb.com/title/tt2379308/&quot;&gt;Psycho-Pass&lt;/a&gt;. People in this world are inseparable from AIs—just like us today. &lt;a href=&quot;https://psychopass.fandom.com/wiki/Toyohisa_Senguji&quot;&gt;Toyohisa Senguji&lt;/a&gt;, a man who replaced every part of himself with machines, asks a question that no longer seems like science fiction:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2026-02-07-invisible-cyborg/toyohisa-senguji.webp&quot; alt=&quot;digital assistant&quot; width=&quot;70%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“You probably have home automation and a digital secretary. What would happen to you if all the data in those devices was lost due to a disaster or accident? When you entrust so much of your everyday life to those electronic devices, the argument that you aren’t a cyborg isn’t very convincing. To you, those portable terminals are already your second brain. Isn’t that right?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We tend to think of ``cyborgs’’ as people with metal limbs. But Senguji suggests we are already there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;building-my-parts-1&quot;&gt;Building my parts&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been using Claude Code primarily for coding and writing. But if they can be a part of me, why not delegate some of my important tasks to them, like task management and planning? Just to see how far they can go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My only concern is that these tasks require another level of trust, and I personally don’t trust them yet to hand over sensitive information to someone behind the AI curtain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily, &lt;a href=&quot;https://ollama.com/&quot;&gt;ollama&lt;/a&gt; recently released a so-called &lt;a href=&quot;https://ollama.com/blog/launch&quot;&gt;ollama launch&lt;/a&gt; feature that lets me use Claude Code with a local model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2026-02-07-invisible-cyborg/ollama-launch.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;70%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;example&quot;&gt;Example&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My day begins with making a daily journal, checking emails and todos, and setting priorities. Then I start my tasks. Sometimes, other work or meetings interrupt me, so I update the journal to reflect changes. Can we automate this process?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I created a simple Claude Slash Command named &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;daily&lt;/code&gt; as follows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-md highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;You are an assistant for daily planning and review.
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;
1.&lt;/span&gt; Confirm the date

Check the date and use the data through the session.

date +&quot;%Y-%m-%d (%A, %B %d, %Y)&quot;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;
2.&lt;/span&gt; Collect data

Gather data from the following sources:
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;
-&lt;/span&gt; Recent Git activity (last 24 hours):
  bash &quot;$TASKS_DIR/scripts/scan_git_changes.sh&quot; &quot;1 day ago&quot;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;
-&lt;/span&gt; OmniFocus tasks:
  osascript &quot;$TASKS_DIR/scripts/get_omnifocus_tasks.scpt&quot;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;
-&lt;/span&gt; Roadmap or goals files in your notes:
  find &quot;$ROADMAP_DIR&quot; -name &quot;&lt;span class=&quot;ge&quot;&gt;*roadmap*&lt;/span&gt;&quot; -o -name &quot;&lt;span class=&quot;ge&quot;&gt;*goals*&lt;/span&gt;&quot; -o -name &quot;&lt;span class=&quot;ge&quot;&gt;*plan*&lt;/span&gt;&quot; | head -20
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;
-&lt;/span&gt; Recent journal entries:
  ls -t &quot;$REVIEWS_DIR&quot;/&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;.md 2&amp;gt;/dev/null | head -3
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;
3.&lt;/span&gt; Triage the data
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;
-&lt;/span&gt; Identify the most important/urgent tasks by project. Highlight flagged/due-soon.
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; Suggest 3-5 key next steps, based on priorities, deadlines, flags, roadmap, and recent progress.
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; Any observations: stalled tasks, idle projects, deadlines, patterns
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;
4.&lt;/span&gt; Write the daily report

Be clear and concise. Use this template:
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;
---&lt;/span&gt;
date: {YYYY-MM-DD}
&lt;span class=&quot;gh&quot;&gt;type: daily-review
---
&lt;/span&gt;
Daily Review — {YYYY-MM-DD}

&lt;span class=&quot;gs&quot;&gt;**What I Did Today**&lt;/span&gt;
{Summarize git changes: commits, files, projects}

&lt;span class=&quot;gs&quot;&gt;**Active OmniFocus Tasks**&lt;/span&gt;
{List most important/urgent tasks by project. Highlight flagged/due-soon.}

&lt;span class=&quot;gs&quot;&gt;**Focus for Today**&lt;/span&gt;
{Suggest 3-5 key next steps, based on priorities, deadlines, flags, roadmap, and recent progress.}

&lt;span class=&quot;gs&quot;&gt;**Notes**&lt;/span&gt;
{Any observations: stalled tasks, idle projects, deadlines, patterns}
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;
5.&lt;/span&gt; Save

Save the review to:
$REVIEWS_DIR/{YYYY-MM-DD}-daily.md

After saving, confirm the file was created and list your top 3 priorities out loud.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;[NOTE]&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Environment variables (like &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;TASKS_DIR&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ROADMAP_DIR&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;REVIEWS_DIR&lt;/code&gt;) are set up for these commands.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;I use existing scripts to collect the needed data.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The “Triage the data” step still needs clearer criteria for setting priorities.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This replaces my morning routine. It checks my data and suggests what I should do today, while I’m caffeinating myself with a cup of coffee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also made other commands, like &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/email&lt;/code&gt;, which helps check my inbox and interacts with me to book meetings, add new tasks, and draft replies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These commands often need to access my calendar and email, but Claude Code alone struggles with that. Using Claude Skills solves this; for example, my &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;calendar&lt;/code&gt; skill lets &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/email&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/daily&lt;/code&gt; work with my calendar app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-do-the-invisible-cyborgs-do-for-me&quot;&gt;What do the invisible cyborgs do for me?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first impression is that the results aren’t quite like mine. They’re longer and more detailed. But, yeah, I can live with it and it saves me about 10 minutes each day. That’s not bad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another unexpected benefit is accountability. I felt like I have someone beside me, checking on my progress and reminding me of my tasks. It helps me stick to my plan and gives me second thoughts, so that I have a broader perspective on what I’m doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve become even more reliant on Claude Code. If I lost access, my productivity would drop more than myself before Claude Code came along.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This resonates with Senguji’s point: if losing your digital secretary would disrupt your life, aren’t they already a part of you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re not waiting for metal limbs to become cyborgs. We’re already there, quietly building ourselves piece by piece.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;random-thoughts&quot;&gt;Random thoughts&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In The Salmon of Doubt, Douglas Adams wrote:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Anything that is in the world when you’re born is normal and ordinary and is just a natural part of the way the world works.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Anything that’s invented between when you’re fifteen and thirty-five is new and exciting and revolutionary and you can probably get a career in it.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Anything invented after you’re thirty-five is against the natural order of things.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To me, the invisible cyborgs are the ones that are against the natural order of things—probably because I’m above thirty-five now. But for younger people, they might be the ones that are normal and ordinary and just a natural part of the way the world works, like those in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imdb.com/title/tt2379308/&quot;&gt;Psycho-Pass&lt;/a&gt; world.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Sadamori Kojaku</name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html">Building my parts</summary></entry></feed>